Guide to the North Carolina State University School of Design Historic Architecture Research Project Records, 1951-1976 UA 110.041
Special Collections Research Center
North Carolina State University School of Design Historic Architecture Research Project Records
1951-1976
UA 110.041
Special Collections Research Center
34.25 Linear feet
The Historic Architecture Research Project Records contain drawings and project files by students in the Department of Architecture, School of Design, at North Carolina State University. Included are measured drawings, photographs, negatives, field notes and sketches, historical information, and essays. The majority of the projects document historic buildings in North Carolina. Twenty-one other states and the District of Columbia are represented, as are Germany, Mexico, and Colombia. Other course-related materials include syllabi, correspondence, uncompleted projects, and a petition to eliminate the course requirement. The correspondence series includes correspondence of professors in the North Carolina State University Department of Architecture, including Cecil D. Elliott, Henry L. Kamphoefner, Vernon Shogren, and Lawrence Wodehouse, with North Carolina State University architecture students, various North Carolina clerks of court, Charles E. Peterson of the National Park Service, and George S. Koyl, Moira B. Mathieson, and Earl H. Reed of the American Institute of Architects.
Between 1951 and 1969, many architecture students at North Carolina State University completed summer projects documenting historic buildings and districts. Beginning in 1959, these projects were submitted to the National Park Service's Historic American Buildings Survey. The project was formalized with the creation of the undergraduate course, "Historic Architecture Research" (ARC 300), which was required for admission to the fifth year architecture program. In 1964, students undertook a project to record the town of Beaufort in Carteret County, N.C. Participants created maps, measured drawings of buildings, and an historical analysis of the town's development.
369 flat files, 24 archival boxes, 1 archival half box, 3 archival card boxes
North Carolina State University. School of Design.
Restrictions to Access
This collection is open for research; access requires at least 24 hours advance notice.
Alternate Form of Material
Some drawings published in: Historic American Buildings Survey [microform]. Cambridge, England: Chadwyck Healey; Teaneck, N.J.: Somerset House, 1980
Acquisitions Information
Transferred from the North Carolina State University School of Design, Dept. of Architecture, 1998 May 27 (Accession no. 1998-0051).
Historical Note
Between 1951 and 1969, many architecture students at North Carolina State University completed summer projects documenting historic buildings and districts. Beginning in 1959, these projects were submitted to the National Park Service's Historic American Buildings Survey. The project was formalized with the creation of the undergraduate course, "Historic Architecture Research" (ARC 300), which was required for admission to the fifth year architecture program. In 1964, students undertook a project to record the town of Beaufort in Carteret County, N.C. Participants created maps, measured drawings of buildings, and an historical analysis of the town's development.
Scope and Content Note
The Historic Architecture Research Project Records contain drawings and project files by students in the Department of Architecture at North Carolina State University. Included are measured drawings, photographs, negatives, field notes and sketches, historical information, and essays. The majority of the projects document historic buildings in North Carolina. Twenty-one other states and the District of Columbia are represented, as are Germany, Mexico, and Colombia. Other course-related materials include syllabi, correspondence, uncompleted projects, and a petition to eliminate the course requirement. The correspondence series includes correspondence of professors in the North Carolina State University Department of Architecture, including Cecil D. Elliott, Henry L. Kamphoefner, Vernon Shogren, and Lawrence Wodehouse, with North Carolina State University architecture students, various North Carolina clerks of court, Charles E. Peterson of the National Park Service, and George S. Koyl, Moira B. Mathieson, and Earl H. Reed of the American Institute of Architects.
Organization of the Collection
This collection is arranged in four series:
1. Projects
2. Correspondence
3. Course-Related Materials and Records
4. Photographs
American Institute of Architects.; Elliott, Cecil D.; Historic American Buildings Survey.; Kamphoefner, Henry Leveke, 1907-1990; Koyl, George S., b. 1885; Mathieson, Moira B.; North Carolina State University. College of Design--History.; North Carolina State University. School of Design--History.; Peterson, Charles E.; Reed, Earl H. (Earl Howell), 1884-1968; Shogren, Vernon; United States. National Park Service. National Architectural and Engineering Records Division.; Wodehouse, Lawrence; Architects--North Carolina--History; Architectural drawing--1950-1970; Architecture--North Carolina--History; Architecture--Study and teaching--North Carolina; Historic buildings--North Carolina; Historic buildings--North Carolina--Photographs; North Carolina--Photographs; Photographs
- UA 110.041 Series 1: Projects, 1951-1976; 32.75 linear feet 369 flat folders, 23 archival boxes, and 1 archival half box
  Scope and Contents note
  The Historic Architecture Research Project Records projects series includes architectural drawings, project notes, photographs, and historical information about subject buildings. Drawings are included for most, but not all, projects. Approximately one-third of the projects include one or more photographs, most of which are in sleeves, though some are mounted on mat board or paper. Most photos are black and white; some sepia and color prints are included as well. Photo sizes vary, ranging from 2" x 2" to 8" x 10".
  Materials are filed by project number. For most projects, there are a flat folder containing oversized drawings and one or two letter-sized folders containing other material, such as field notes, photographs, or smaller drawings.
  - North Carolina, Wake County, Raleigh: Dix Hill [Dorothea Dix Hospital] Drawings, 3 drawings (Folder 1.1)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, Raleigh: Dix Hill [Dorothea Dix Hospital] Field notes (Box 1, Folder 1.2)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, Raleigh: St. Mary's College Chapel Drawings, 10 drawings (Folder 2.1)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, Raleigh: St. Mary's College Chapel Field notes (Box 1, Folder 2.2)
  - New York, Nassau County, Oyster Bay: Raynham Hall Drawings, 8 drawings (Folder 3.1)
  - New York, Nassau County, Oyster Bay: Raynham Hall Field notes (Box 1, Folder 3.2)
  - Connecticut, New London County, Lebanon: Governor Jonathan Trumbull's War Office Drawings, 12 drawings (Folder 4.1)
  - Connecticut, New London County, Lebanon: Governor Jonathan Trumbull's War Office Field notes (Box 1, Folder 4.2)
  - Connecticut, New London County, Lebanon: Governor Jonathan Trumbull's War Office Photographs (Box 1, Folder 4.3)
  - North Carolina, Franklin County: Tobacco Barn Drawings, 2 drawings (Folder 5.1)
  - North Carolina, Franklin County: Tobacco Barn Field notes, photographs (Box 1, Folder 5.2)
  - North Carolina, Moore County, Southern Pines: Shaw House Drawings, 6 drawings (Folder 6.1)
  - North Carolina, Moore County, Southern Pines: Shaw House Field notes, photographs (Box 1, Folder 6.2)
  - Maryland, Prince George's County, Fort Washington: Sallyport Entrance Drawings, 8 drawings (Folder 7.1)
  - Maryland, Prince George's County, Fort Washington: Sallyport Entrance Field notes (Box 1, Folder 7.2)
  - Maryland, Prince George's County, Fort Washington: Sallyport Entrance Photographs (Box 1, Folder 7.3)
  - North Carolina, Wake County: Hollands Methodist Church Drawings, 7 drawings (Folder 8.1)
  - North Carolina, Wake County: Hollands Methodist Church Field notes (Box 1, Folder 8.2)
  - North Carolina, Wake County: Hollands Methodist Church Photographs (Box 1, Folder 8.3)
  - North Carolina, Duplin County, Kenansville: Grove Presbyterian Church Drawings, 9 drawings (Folder 9.1)
  - North Carolina, Duplin County, Kenansville: Grove Presbyterian Church Field notes, photographs (Box 1, Folder 9.2)
  - North Carolina, Rowan County: Third Creek Presbyterian Church Drawings, 4 drawings (Folder 10.1)
  - North Carolina, Rowan County: Third Creek Presbyterian Church Field notes (Box 1, Folder 10.2)
  - North Carolina, Forsyth County, Winston Salem (Old Salem): Mural House Field notes [drawings missing] (Box 1, Folder 11.1)
  - South Carolina, York County (item reads Cherokee County): Henry Howser Residence [same as project 323] Drawings, 3 drawings (Folder 12.1)
  - South Carolina, York County (item reads Cherokee County): Henry Howser Residence [same as project 323] Field notes (Box 1, Folder 12.2)
  - South Carolina, York County (item reads Cherokee County): Henry Howser Residence [same as project 323] Photographs (Box 1, Folder 12.3)
  - North Carolina, Johnston County, Smithfield: Elizabeth Methodist Church Drawings [some missing], 8 drawings (Folder 13.1)
  - North Carolina, Johnston County, Smithfield: Elizabeth Methodist Church Field notes, photographs (Box 1, Folder 13.2)
  - North Carolina, New Hanover County, Wilmington: Honnett House Drawings, 7 drawings (Folder 14.1)
  - North Carolina, New Hanover County, Wilmington: Honnett House Field notes (Box 1, Folder 14.2)
  - North Carolina, New Hanover County, Wilmington: Honnett House Photographs, negatives (Box 1, Folder 14.3)
  - North Carolina, Mecklenburg County, Dixie: Col. Benjamin Franklin Brown House Drawings, 9 drawings (Folder 15.1)
  - North Carolina, Mecklenburg County, Dixie: Col. Benjamin Franklin Brown House Field notes, photographs (Box 1, Folder 15.2)
  - North Carolina, Halifax County, Halifax: Constitution House Drawings, 6 drawings (Folder 16.1)
  - North Carolina, Halifax County, Halifax: Constitution House Field notes, photographs (Box 1, Folder 16.2)
  - New York, Niagra County, Youngstown: Castle at Old Ft. Niagara Drawings, 4 drawings (Folder 17.1)
  - New York, Niagra County, Youngstown: Castle at Old Ft. Niagara Field notes, photograph (Box 1, Folder 17.2)
  - Massachusetts, Berkshire County, Adams: Quaker Meeting House Drawings, 5 drawings (Folder 18.1)
  - Massachusetts, Berkshire County, Adams: Quaker Meeting House Field notes, photographs (Box 1, Folder 18.2)
  - North Carolina, Guilford County, Greensboro: Sherwood House Drawings, 6 drawings (Folder 19.1)
  - North Carolina, Guilford County, Greensboro: Sherwood House Field notes, photographs (Box 1, Folder 19.2)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, Apex/Cary vicinity: Farmhouse [a.k.a. Joseph Lane House, same as project 253] Drawings, 4 drawings (Folder 20.1)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, Apex/Cary vicinity: Farmhouse [a.k.a. Joseph Lane House, same as project 253] Field notes (Box 1, Folder 20.2)
  - Florida, St. John's County, St. Augustine: City Gate Drawings, 2 drawings (Folder 21.1)
  - Florida, St. John's County, St. Augustine: City Gate Field notes, photographs (Box 1, Folder 21.2)
  - North Carolina, Washington County: Colony House, Collens [i..e., Collins] Place [Somerset Place] Drawings, 6 drawings (Folder 22.1)
  - North Carolina, Washington County: Colony House, Collens [i..e., Collins] Place [Somerset Place] Field notes (Box 2, Folder 22.2)
  - District of Columbia, Washington [Georgetown]: C & O Canal Lock, House at Lock II Drawings, 4 drawings (Folder 23.1)
  - District of Columbia, Washington [Georgetown]: C & O Canal Lock, House at Lock II Field notes, photographs (Box 2, Folder 23.2)
  - North Carolina, Wake County: Yates Mill Drawings [blue line prints, 1 original, some sheets missing] [field notes missing], 12 drawings (Folder 24.1)
  - North Carolina, Orange County, Chapel Hill: Old West, UNC Drawings, 2 drawings (Folder 25.1)
  - North Carolina, Orange County, Chapel Hill: Old West, UNC Field notes, photographs (Box 2, Folder 25.2)
  - North Carolina, Carteret County, Beaufort vicinity: Fort Macon Drawings, 7 drawings (Folder 26.1)
  - North Carolina, Carteret County, Beaufort vicinity: Fort Macon Field notes (Box 2, Folder 26.2)
  - North Carolina, Catawba County, Conover: St. Paul's Lutheran Church Drawings, 4 drawings (Folder 27.1)
  - North Carolina, Catawba County, Conover: St. Paul's Lutheran Church Field notes (Box 2, Folder 27.2)
  - Colombia, Medellin: House Calle Sucre Drawings, 4 drawings (Folder 28.1)
  - Colombia, Medellin: House Calle Sucre Field notes (Box 2, Folder 28.2)
  - North Carolina, Bladen County, Tar Heel: Beth Car Presbyterian Church Drawings, 5 drawings (Folder 29.1)
  - North Carolina, Bladen County, Tar Heel: Beth Car Presbyterian Church Oversized sketches, 5 drawings (Folder 29.2)
  - North Carolina, Bladen County, Tar Heel: Beth Car Presbyterian Church Field notes, photographs (Box 2, Folder 29.3)
  - North Carolina, Iredell County, Statesville: W.D. Summers Homestead Drawings, 6 drawings (Folder 30.1)
  - North Carolina, Iredell County, Statesville: W.D. Summers Homestead Field notes (Box 2, Folder 30.2)
  - North Carolina, Randolph County, Randleman: St. Paul's Methodist Church Drawings, 3 drawings (Folder 31.1)
  - North Carolina, Randolph County, Randleman: St. Paul's Methodist Church Field notes (Box 2, Folder 31.2)
  - North Carolina, Moore County: Union Presbyterian Church Drawings, 7 drawings (Folder 32.1)
  - North Carolina, Moore County: Union Presbyterian Church Field notes (Box 2, Folder 32.2)
  - North Carolina, Cumberland County, Fort Bragg: Longstreet Presbyterian Church Drawings, 3 drawings (Folder 33.1)
  - North Carolina, Cumberland County, Fort Bragg: Longstreet Presbyterian Church Field notes (Box 2, Folder 33.2)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, Cary: Nancy Jones House Field notes, photographs [drawings missing], 0 drawings (Box 2, Folder 34.1)
  - District of Columbia, Washington [Georgetown]: Union Engine House Drawings, 5 drawings (Folder 35.1)
  - District of Columbia, Washington [Georgetown]: Union Engine House Field notes, photographs (Box 2, Folder 35.2)
  - North Carolina, Bladen County: Old Brown Marsh Presbyterian Church Drawings, 2 drawings (Folder 36.1)
  - North Carolina, Bladen County: Old Brown Marsh Presbyterian Church Field notes, photographs (Box 2, Folder 36.2)
  - North Carolina, Allegheny County: Brinegar Cabin Drawings, 2 drawings (Folder 37.1)
  - North Carolina, Allegheny County: Brinegar Cabin Field notes (Box 2, Folder 37.2)
  - North Carolina, Guilford County, Greensboro: Bumpass House [same as project 213] Drawings, 6 drawings (Folder 38.1)
  - North Carolina, Guilford County, Greensboro: Bumpass House [same as project 213] Field notes, photographs (Box 2, Folder 38.2)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, Raleigh: Heartt House Drawings, 10 drawings (Folder 39.1)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, Raleigh: Heartt House Field notes (Box 2, Folder 39.2)
  - North Carolina, Franklin County: Henry T. Wall Residence Drawings, 7 drawings (Folder 40.1)
  - North Carolina, Franklin County: Henry T. Wall Residence Field notes (Box 2, Folder 40.2)
  - Vermont, Windsor County, Weston: Farrar Mansure House Drawings, 8 drawings (Folder 41.1)
  - Vermont, Windsor County, Weston: Farrar Mansure House Field notes (Box 2, Folder 41.2)
  - North Carolina, Caldwell County: Corpening Residence Drawings, 5 drawings (Folder 42.1)
  - North Carolina, Caldwell County: Corpening Residence Field notes, photographs (Box 2, Folder 42.2)
  - North Carolina, Lee County, Sanford: Scott-Iver House Drawings, 3 drawings (Folder 43.1)
  - North Carolina, Lee County, Sanford: Scott-Iver House Field notes (Box 2, Folder 43.2)
  - North Carolina, Cabarrus County: McCurdy House Drawings, 11 drawings (Folder 44.1)
  - North Carolina, Cabarrus County: McCurdy House Field notes (Box 2, Folder 44.2)
  - North Carolina, Cabarrus County: McCurdy House Photographs (Box 2, Folder 44.3)
  - Tennessee, Greene County, Greeneville: First Andrew Johnson House Drawings [sepia prints, originals missing], 5 drawings (Folder 45.1)
  - Tennessee, Greene County, Greeneville: First Andrew Johnson House Field notes (Box 2, Folder 45.2)
  - New Jersey, Union County, Cranford: Home of Josiah Crane, Sr. Drawings, 3 drawings (Folder 46.1)
  - New Jersey, Union County, Cranford: Home of Josiah Crane, Sr. Field notes, photographs (Box 2, Folder 46.2)
  - Minnesota, Bovey: Isaak Mackmen Homestead Drawings, 4 drawings (Folder 47.1)
  - Minnesota, Bovey: Isaak Mackmen Homestead Field notes, photographs (Box 2, Folder 47.2)
  - New York, Queens County, Flushing: Friends Meeting House Drawings, 4 drawings (Folder 48.1)
  - New York, Queens County, Flushing: Friends Meeting House Field notes, photographs (Box 2, Folder 48.2)
  - North Carolina, Mecklenburg County, Charlotte: Alexander House [same as project 148] Drawings, 3 drawings (Folder 49.1)
  - North Carolina, Mecklenburg County, Charlotte: Alexander House [same as project 148]Field notes (Box 2, Folder 49.2)
  - Colombia, Bogota: Wartime Home of Simon Bolivar Drawings, 5 drawings (Folder 50.1)
  - Colombia, Bogota: Wartime Home of Simon Bolivar Field notes (Box 2, Folder 50.2)
  - North Carolina, Wayne County, Fremont: Charles B. Aycock Birthplace Drawings, 3 drawings (Folder 51.1)
  - North Carolina, Wayne County, Fremont: Charles B. Aycock Birthplace Field notes (Box 2, Folder 51.2)
  - North Carolina, Wayne County, Fremont: Charles B. Aycock Birthplace Photographs (Box 2, Folder 51.3)
  - North Carolina, Durham County, Durham: Tobacco Factory of Washington Duke Drawings, 5 drawings (Folder 52.1)
  - North Carolina, Durham County, Durham: Tobacco Factory of Washington Duke Field notes, photographs (Box 2, Folder 52.2)
  - North Carolina, Randolph County: House (currently property of Mrs. Verla C. Wallace, High Point) Drawings, 4 drawings (Folder 53.1)
  - North Carolina, Randolph County: House (currently property of Mrs. Verla C. Wallace, High Point)Field notes, photographs (Box 2, Folder 53.2)
  - New York, Dutchess County, Fiskhill: Reformed Dutch Church Drawings, 11 drawings (Folder 54.1)
  - New York, Dutchess County, Fiskhill: Reformed Dutch Church Field notes (Box 3, Folder 54.2)
  - North Carolina, Caswell County, Milton: Milton Presbyterian Church Drawings, 5 drawings (Folder 55.1)
  - North Carolina, Caswell County, Milton: Milton Presbyterian Church Field notes, photographs (Box 3, Folder 55.2)
  - North Carolina, Montgomery County: Zion Methodist Church Drawings, 6 drawings (Folder 56.1)
  - North Carolina, Montgomery County: Zion Methodist Church Field notes, photographs (Box 3, Folder 56.2)
  - Louisiana, New Orleans: Lafitte Brothers' Blacksmith Shop Drawings, 3 drawings (Folder 57.1)
  - Louisiana, New Orleans: Lafitte Brothers' Blacksmith Shop Field notes (Box 3, Folder 57.2)
  - North Carolina, Orange County, Chapel Hill: Playmaker's Theater, UNC Drawings, 5 drawings (Folder 58.1)
  - North Carolina, Orange County, Chapel Hill: Playmaker's Theater, UNC Field notes, photographs (Box 3, Folder 58.2)
  - Connecticut, Hartford County, Wethersfield: Cove Warehouse Drawings, 5 drawings (Folder 59.1)
  - Connecticut, Hartford County, Wethersfield: Cove Warehouse Field notes, photographs (Box 3, Folder 59.2)
  - North Carolina, Rowan County, Granite Quarry: Ye Ole Stone House [same as project 96] Drawings, 3 drawings (Folder 60.1)
  - North Carolina, Rowan County, Granite Quarry: Ye Ole Stone House [same as project 96] Field notes (Box 3, Folder 60.2)
  - North Carolina, Guilford County: Thompson House Drawings, 7 drawings (Folder 61.1)
  - North Carolina, Guilford County: Thompson House Field notes (Box 3, Folder 61.2)
  - North Carolina, Martin County, Hamilton: St. Martin's Episcopal Church Drawings, 8 drawings (Folder 62.1)
  - North Carolina, Martin County, Hamilton: St. Martin's Episcopal Church Field notes (Box 3, Folder 62.2)
  - North Carolina, Martin County, Hamilton: St. Martin's Episcopal Church Photographs (Box 3, Folder 62.3)
  - Michigan, Birmingham: John West Hunter House Drawings, 4 drawings (Folder 63.1)
  - Michigan, Birmingham: John West Hunter House Field notes (Box 3, Folder 63.2)
  - Virginia, Albemarle County, Zion's Crossroads: Beverdam Baptist Church Drawings, 7 drawings (Folder 64.1)
  - Virginia, Albemarle County, Zion's Crossroads: Beverdam Baptist Church Field notes (Box 3, Folder 64.2)
  - North Carolina, Gaston County, Stanley: Clint Moore House Drawings, 6 drawings (Folder 65.1)
  - North Carolina, Gaston County, Stanley: Clint Moore House Field notes (Box 3, Folder 65.2)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, Raleigh: Haywood House Drawings, 6 drawings (Folder 66.1)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, Raleigh: Haywood House Field notes (Box 3, Folder 66.2)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, Raleigh: Wakefield [a.k.a. Joel Lane House] Drawings, 2 drawings (Folder 67.1)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, Raleigh: Wakefield [a.k.a. Joel Lane House] Field notes (Box 3, Folder 67.2)
  - North Carolina, Orange County, Chapel Hill: Chapel of the Cross Drawings, 7 drawings (Folder 68.1)
  - North Carolina, Orange County, Chapel Hill: Chapel of the Cross Field notes, photographs, reduced drawings (Box 3, Folder 68.2)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, Raleigh: Wynne Residence Drawings, 8 drawings (Folder 69.1)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, Raleigh: Wynne Residence Field notes (Box 3, Folder 69.2)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, Raleigh: Wynne Residence Photographs, reduced drawings (Box 3, Folder 69.3)
  - Alabama, Lauderdale County, Florence: Forks of Cypress Drawings, 6 drawings (Folder 70.1)
  - Alabama, Lauderdale County, Florence: Forks of Cypress Field notes, photographs (Box 3, Folder 70.2)
  - North Carolina, Mecklenburg County: Wallis House Drawings, 6 drawings (Folder 71.1)
  - North Carolina, Mecklenburg County: Wallis House Field notes, photographs (Box 3, Folder 71.2)
  - North Carolina, Moore County, Carbonton: House in the Horseshoe Drawings, 10 drawings (Folder 72.1)
  - North Carolina, Moore County, Carbonton: House in the Horseshoe Field notes, photographs (Box 3, Folder 72.2)
  - North Carolina, Catawba County, Newton: Old St. Paul's Church Drawings, 6 drawings (Folder 73.1)
  - North Carolina, Catawba County, Newton: Old St. Paul's Church Field notes, photographs (Box 3, Folder 73.2)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, New Hill: Richardson's Place Drawings, 4 drawings (Folder 74.1)
  - North Carolina, Wake County, New Hill: Richardson's Place Field notes, photographs (Box 3, Folder 74.2)
  - North Carolina, Union County, Monroe: City Hall (originally jail) Drawings, 4 drawings (Folder 75.1)
  - North Carolina, Union County, Monroe: City Hall (originally jail) Field notes (Box 4, Folder 75.2)
  - North Carolina, Orange County, Hillsborough: Isaac Edwards Office (Nash-Kollock Female Academy after 1859)Drawings, 8 drawings (Folder 76.1)
  - North Carolina, Orange County, Hillsborough: Isaac Edwards Office (Nash-Kollock Female Academy after 1859)Field notes, photograph (Box 4, Folder 76.2)
  - New York, New York County, New York: No. 100 Bedford Street, Greenwich Village Drawings, 6 drawings (Folder 77.1)
  - New York, New York County, New York: No. 100 Bedford Street, Greenwich Village Field notes, photographs (Box 4, Folder 77.2)
  - Virginia, Princess Anne County: Adam Keeling House Drawings, 5 drawings (Folder 78.1)
  - Virginia, Princess Anne County: Adam Keeling House Field notes, photographs (Box 4, Folder 78.2)
  - North Carolina, Beaufort County, Bath: St. Thomas Episcopal Church Drawings, 5 drawings (Folder 79.1)
  - North Carolina, Beaufort County, Bath: St. Thomas Episcopal Church Field notes, photographs (Box 4, Folder 79.2)